# Tej Chajed

### Curriculum Vitae



#### Research Interests

I work on formal verification for systems software. In my research I develop **realistic**, **performant systems**, specify their intended behavior, then prove that the implementation always meet the specification. My PhD research culminated in a **verified**, **concurrent file system** with a proof that your data is safe if the computer suddenly reboots, and which gets good performance.

#### Education

- 2014–2022 **Ph.D. in Computer Science**, MIT, Cambridge, MA Verifying a concurrent, crash-safe file system with sequential reasoning
- 2014–2017 M.S. in Computer Science, GPA: 4.0/4.0, MIT, Cambridge, MA Verifying an I/O-concurrent file system
- 2010–2014 **B.S. in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science**, GPA: 3.97/4.0, University of Illinois, Urbana, IL

#### Positions

- 2023–present Assistant professor, University of Wisconsin-Madison
  - 2022–2023 **Postdoctoral researcher**, at VMware Research
  - 2014–2022 **Research assistant**, at MIT in the PDOS group advised by Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich, and Joseph Tassarotti

#### Conference Publications

- VLDB 2023 **DBSP: Automatic Incremental View Maintenance for Rich Query Languages** 
  - Mihai Budiu, Tej Chajed, Frank McSherry, Leonid Ryzhyk, Val Tannen
- OSDI 2022 Verifying the DaisyNFS concurrent and crash-safe file system with sequential reasoning
  - Tej Chajed, Joseph Tassarotti, Mark Theng, M. Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich
- OSDI 2021 **GoJournal: a verified, concurrent, crash-safe journaling system**Tej Chajed, Joseph Tassarotti, Mark Theng, Ralf Jung, M. Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich
- SOSP 2019 Verifying concurrent, crash-safe systems with Perennial Tej Chajed, Joseph Tassarotti, M. Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich

- Security 2019 EverParse: Verified Secure Zero-Copy Parsers for Authenticated Message Formats

  Tahina Ramananandro, Antoine Delignat-Layaud, Cédric Fournet, Nikhil Swamy, Tei
  - Tahina Ramananandro, Antoine Delignat-Lavaud, Cédric Fournet, Nikhil Swamy, *Tej Chajed*, Nadim Kobeissi, Jonathan Protzenko
  - PLDI 2019 Argosy: Verifying Layered Storage Systems with Recovery Refinement *Tej Chajed*, Joseph Tassarotti, M. Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich
  - OSDI 2018 Verifying concurrent software using movers in CSPEC

    Tej Chajed, M. Frans Kaashoek, Butler Lampson, and Nickolai Zeldovich
  - OSDI 2018 **Proving confidentiality in a file system using DiskSec**Atalay İleri, *Tej Chajed*, Adam Chlipala, M. Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich
  - SOSP 2017 Verifying a high-performance crash-safe file system using a tree specification
    Haogang Chen, *Tej Chajed*, Alex Konradi, Stephanie Wang, Atalay İleri, Adam Chlipala,
    M. Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich
  - SOSP 2015 Using Crash Hoare Logic for certifying the FSCQ file system
    Haogang Chen, Daniel Ziegler, *Tej Chajed*, Adam Chlipala, M. Frans Kaashoek, and
    Nickolai Zeldovich
  - SoCC 2013 Natjam: design and evaluation of eviction policies for supporting priorities and deadlines in mapreduce clusters

    Brian Cho, Muntasir Rahman, *Tej Chajed*, Indranil Gupta, Cristina Abad, Nathan Roberts, Philbert Lin

### Workshop Papers

- CoqPL 2021 Record Updates in Coq Tej Chajed
- CoqPL 2020 Verifying concurrent Go code in Coq with Goose

  Tej Chajed, Joseph Tassarotti, M. Frans Kaashoek, Nickolai Zeldovich
- HotOS 2015 **Amber: Decoupling user data from web applications**Tej Chajed, Jon Gjengset, Jelle van den Hooff, M. Frans Kaashoek, James Mickens, Robert Morris, Nickolai Zeldovich

# Teaching Experiences

- Fall 2023 Instructor, CS 839: Systems verification, UW-Madison
- Fall 2020 TA, 6.826 (Principles of Computer Systems), MIT
- Fall 2019 TA, 6.826 (Principles of Computer Systems), MIT
- Fall 2017 TA, 6.826 (Principles of Computer Systems), MIT
- Spring 2017 **Course development**, 6.826 (Principles of Computer Systems), MIT During this time I designed and implemented the programming assignments for 6.826.

### Mentorship

- 2022 Mark Theng (master's thesis)
- 2021 Sharon Lin, undergrad

- 2020 Sydney Gibson (master's thesis)
- 2019 Eleftherios Ioannidis (master's thesis)
- 2017 Alex Konradi (master's thesis)
- 2017 Daniel Ziegler (master's thesis)

### Industry Experience

- Summer Research Intern, Microsoft Research, Cambridge, UK
  - 2017 Verifying low-level parsing in F\*, with Cédric Fournet
- Summer Software Engineering Intern, Google, Zürich, Switzerland
  - 2014

## — Honors & Awards

- 2022 Dennis Ritchie Doctoral Dissertation Award Honorable Mention (SIGOPS)
- 2022 George M. Sprowls PhD Thesis Award (MIT)
- 2014–2019 NSF Graduate Research Fellowship
  - 2014 Jacobs Presidential Fellowship
- 2010–2014 Chancellor's Scholar

#### Professional Service

- PLDI 2024 Program Committee
- SySDW 2023 Program Committee
  - CPP 2023 Program Committee
  - POPL 2023 Program Committee
  - PLDI 2022 Program Committee
  - POPL 2021 Organized a tutorial "Iris A Modular Foundation for Higher-Order Concurrent Separation Logic"

### References

Frans Kaashoek

kaashoek@mit.edu

Nickolai Zeldovich

nickolai@csail.mit.edu

Joseph Tassarotti

joseph.tassarotti@bc.edu